Inventory of the W. W. Morrison Papers, 1804-1977
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
- Research Files, 1945-1973 (Box 9)
  - Oregon Trail: investigations of the route, landmarks, graves and events
    - Fort Laramie to Register Cliff: includes list of forts in Wyoming
    - Register Cliff to Horse Shoe Station: includes list of names at Register Cliff, Emigrant Springs, etc.; Cottonwood Creek; graves of J.D. Stokes, S. Dill, Ann Scott, W. Page, K. Wood, Courtfoot, John F. Miller, etc.
    - Horse Shoe Station to Deer Creek: Bridger Ferry; Indian Wars; LaBonte; Fort Fetterman; graves of J. Hembree, C.B. Platt, etc.
    - Deer Creek to Fort Casper: graves of C.B. Platt, J.P. Parker, Martin Ringo; Platte Bridge fight; Mormon ferry, etc.
    - Fort Casper: Platte Bridge fight; Custard and Collins Massacres; Platte River crossings, etc.
    - Fort Casper to Sweetwater: Platte Bridge; Independence Rock; graves of Rachel Morgan and others; Devil's Gate, etc.
    - Sweetwater: Independence Rock; Devil's Gate; South Pass; graves of T.P. Baker, Jo Barnette and Mrs. Bryan; Cattle Kate lynching, etc.
    - Sweetwater to Green River: Pacific Springs; Sublette Cutoff; South Pass; Green River ferry, etc.
    - Green River to Fort Boise: Fort Hall; Indian massacres, etc.
    - Fort Boise to Columbia River: grave of Jane Hobart; Wallowa Lake; Chief Joseph; Whitman Mission, etc.
    - Columbia River, Oregon and Washington; graves of Frances Keeney; Astoria; the Dalles and Cascades; Mount Hood; missions and early explorations, etc.
    - Full Route: miscellaneous notes
  - Overland Trail, primarily Wyoming and Colorado: Virginia Dale; Jack Slade; graves, etc., 1945-1973
  - Cutoffs and short trails
    - Lodgepole Creek Trail, Nebraska and Southeastern Wyoming: graves of Emly Patrick; Sherman Station and Sherman Hill; Union Pacific route, etc., 1945-1973
    - Deadwood Trail, Wyoming and South Dakota: ranches, etc., 1947
    - Blue Bucket Mine Trail (Meek Cutoff), Oregon: grave of Mrs. S. Chambers; Lost Wagon Train, etc., 1947-1948
    - Barlow Road, Oregon: also Oregon Territory Centennial, 1947-1950
    - Vancouver to Olympia, Washington: Indians and Indian battles; early exploration; Talcott family, etc., 1945-1973
- Research Files, 1945-1974 (Box 10)
  - Willamette Valley, Oregon: Oregon City; Oregon Territory Centennial, etc., 1945-1972
  - Rock Creek Methodist Church, Oregon: regarding restoration as a historic landmark, 1949-1953, 2 files
  - Northern Oregon: general history and personal interest, 1945-1974, 2 files
  - Southern Oregon: general history and personal interest, 1953-1973
  - Washington State: Chambers family; Fort Vancouver; general history, etc., 1948-1951
- Research Notes, no dates (Box 10)
  Transcripts from books and other published sources
  - Early Explorations and the Fur Trade
    - Astoria/Pierre Dorion/The Tonquin, 2 files
    - Bent's Fort
    - John Bozeman/Jim Bridger/Jean-Baptiste Charbonneau/John Colter/Hugh Glass/Sacajawea/Jane Silcott
    - Fremont's expeditions
    - Wyoming, early settlement
  - Indian Wars
    - Chronological List Of Actions Etc. With Indians From Jan. 1866 to Jan. 1891
    - Custer Massacre/Commanche, the horse that survived the massacre/Dull Knife battlefield/Fort McKinney/Fort Mackenzie
    - Fort Phil Kearny and the Fetterman Massacre/Wagon Box fight/Connor battlefield/Medicine Wheel
    - Platte Bridge/Plum Creek, Potter and Ogallala/Summit Springs battles 1865-1870
    - Spotted Tail and Crazy Horse/Capt. Eugene Ware's reminiscences
  - Mining Towns: Montana Vigilantes/H.A.W. Tabor/Klondike Kate/Prostitutes/Soapy Smith, etc.
  - Oregon Trail
    - from Along the Trail, no author, no date
    - from The Ferries of the Forty-Niners, by D.L. Morgan, 1959
    - from The Great Platte River Road, by M.J. Mattes, 1969
    - from The Road to Oregon, by W.J. Ghent, 1934
    - Courthouse Rock, Jail Rock and Independence Rock
    - Emigration of 1842
    - Emigration of 1843
    - Emigration of 1845
    - Pioneers and Pioneer Life: abuse and death of animals/types of transportation/wayside post offices/women on the trail, etc.
  - Overland Stage and Pony Express
    - from The Overland Stage to California - the Pony Express, by F. Root and W.E. Connelley, 1901
    - from The Pony Express, by A. Chapman, 1932
    - Pony Express Route in Wyoming, report to Wyoming Pony Express Centennial Board, 1959
  - Ranching
    - Tom Horn: from The Saga of Tom Horn, by D. Krakel, 1954; and "The Hanging Of Tom Horn", by J.C. Thompson, 1945
    - The hard winter of 1886-1887, from Forty Years on the Frontier, by G. Stewart, no date
  - Railroads: building the first transcontinental line
  - States
    - Kansas and Nebraska: settling Kansas/Harney Massacre/Fort Kearney
    - Nevada and Utah: general history
    - Oregon: geology, paleontology and early history/Fort Vancouver/transportation and settlements, etc.
    - Washington: geology, paleontology, geography, history, settlements, etc.
    - Wyoming
      - Cheyenne, history and early churches
      - Cheyenne Leader, transcripts from newspapers, 1867-1878, 4 files
      - from History of Wyoming, by C.G. Coutant, n.d., etc.
- Research Notes, no dates (Box 11)
  - Folk lore of Oregon and Washington
  - Jesse James: from Pictorial History of the Wild West, by J.D. Horan and P. Sann, 1954
  - Abraham Lincoln
    - from Lincoln the President, by J.G. Randall, 1945
    - from When Lincoln Died, by R. Borreson, no date
  - Europe: Mount Vesuvius/St. Paul at Puteoli/Pompeii/Rome/Paris
  - Tahiti: from Tahiti, by J. Conrad including history, description, story of the Bounty
- Subject Files, 1953-1974 (Box 11)
  - English Composition: class notes and handouts for expository writing class taken at Laramie Community College, Cheyenne, 1974
  - Short Story Composition, class outline, 1970
  - Trail Treks
    - Oregon Trail Trek no.1, June 28, 1953, from Nebraska-Wyoming border to Guernsey; maps, photographs, itinerary and program, 2 files
    - Oregon Trail Trek no.2, Oct. 25, 1953, from Guernsey to Fort Fetterman; maps, itinerary and program, 2 files
    - Oregon Trail Trek no.3, May 30, 1954, from Hunton Ranch to Fort Casper; itinerary and program
    - Emigrant Trail Trek no.10, July 3-5, 1959, from Fort Laramie to Fort Casper; maps, itinerary and program
- Transcripts, 1936-1969 (Box 11)
  Of magazine articles, newspapers, pamphlets, books; not relating to western history
  - "Man's Best Friend", 1969
  - "My Will For Those I Love", no date
  - "New Facts Unearthed Shedding Light On The Christmas Story", 1969
  - "The Proper Way To Write Letters", 1960
  - "Seven Reasons Why A Scientist Believes In God", 1946
  - "The Story Of Our Bible"/"The Open Grave", 1936
  - "An Unfinished Diary", 1965
  - "Why I Am For The Churches", 1951
  - Poetry and epigrams, 3 files
- Books, 1932-1949 (Box 11)
  - Adams, J.T., The Epic of America, 1932
  - Beard, J.W., Saddles East: Horseback Over the Old Oregon Trail, 1949
  - Bible Hand Book, 1934
  - Bible Readings for the Home Circle, 1920
  - Bible Stories, 1941
  - Book of Jasher, 1934
  - Book of Mormon, 1948
  - Brooks, N., The Boy Emigrants, 1920
- Books, 1885-1971 (Box 12)
  - Bruff, J.G., Gold Rush, 1949
  - Burkard, W.E., R.L. Chambers, F.W. Maroney, Health for Young Americans, 1946
  - Burroughs, J.R., Guardian of the Grasslands: the First Hundred Years of the Wyoming Stock Growers Association, 1971
  - Chapman, L.H., Using English, First Year, 1938
  - Clarke, S.A., Pioneer Days of Oregon History, Vols.1-2, 1905
  - Collier, R., The Secret of the Ages, 1959
  - Connelley, W.E., Wyandot Folk-Lore, 1899
  - Conner, R., Black Rock: A Tale of the Selkirks, no date
  - Coons, F.B., The Trail to Oregon, 1954
  - Crowther, M.O., How to Write Letters, 1941
  - Custer, E.B., Boots and Saddles, 1885, 1st edition
  - Deming, W.C., Collected Writings and Addresses, Vol. 1, 1946, autographed
- Books, 1902-1956 (Box 13)
  - DeVoto, B., Across the Wide Missouri, 1947
  - DeVoto, B., The Journals of Lewis and Clark, 1953
  - DeVoto, B., The Year of Decision 1846, 1943
  - Driggs, H.R., George, the Handcart Boy, 1952, autographed
  - Driggs, H.R., Living English, Fifth Grade, 1935, autographed
  - Driggs, H.R., Mormon Trail, 1947, autographed, 2 copies
  - Driggs, H.R., The Old West Speaks, 1956, autographed
  - Driggs, H.R., The Pony Express Goes Through, 1935
  - Driggs, H.R., Timpanogos Town, 1948, autographed, 3 copies
  - Driggs, H.R., Westward America, 1942, autographed
  - Duniway, A.S., From the West to the West, 1905, autographed
  - Duniway, A.S., Path Breaking: An Autobiographical History of the Equal Suffrage Movement in Pacific Coast States, 1914
  - Dye, E.E., The Conquest: The True Story of Lewis and Clark, 1902
  - Dye, E.E., The Soul of America: An Oregon Iliad, 1934
- Books, 1906-1965 (Box 14)
  - Edwards, T., A Dictionary of Thoughts, 1906
  - Ehernberger, J.L., F.G. Gschwind, Smoke Over the Divide: Union Pacific, Wyoming Division
  - Fairbanks, D., Laugh and Live, 1917
  - Felleman, H. (ed.), The Best Loved Poems of the American People, 1936
  - Fisher, V., Children of God, 1939
  - Florin, L., Tales the Western Tombstones Tell, no date, 1st edition
    (includes article by W.W. Morrison on Ada Magill)
  - Garst, D.S., The Story of Wyoming, 1938, (mildewed)
  - Gates, S.Y., L.D. Widtsoe, Life Story of Brigham Young, 1930
  - Ghent, W.J., The Road to Oregon, 1934
  - Gibbons, F., The Red Knight of Germany: The Story of Baron Von Richthofen, 1959
  - Hammarskjold, D., Markings, 1964
  - Harrington, H.F., T.T. Frankenberg, Essentials in Journalism, 1912
  - Hebard, G.R., E.A. Brininstool, The Bozeman Trail, Vol.1, 1922
  - Heolstrom, C.B., Pay-Day - Some Day, 1938
  - Hendricks, R.J., Bethel and Aurora, 1933
  - Hicks, J.D., The Federal Union, 1937
  - Hooker, W.F., The Bullwhacker, 1940
- Books, 1872-1974 (Box 15)
  - Horner, J.B., Oregon, 1921
  - Hough, E., The Covered Wagon, 1922
  - Hoyle, F., The Nature of the Universe, 1955
  - Kelly, F., Narrative of My Captivity Among the Sioux Indians, 1 copy 1872 edition, 1 copy 1873 edition
  - Kennedy, R.F., Times to Remember, 1974
  - Lamb, C., Tales from Shakespeare, no date, incomplete
  - Larson, T.A., History of Wyoming, 1965 (water-damaged)
  - Lewis, N., New Power with Words, 1964
  - Long, M., The Smoky Hill Trail, 1947
  - Long, W.J., America: A History of Our Country, 1923
  - Martin, R.G., The Woman He Loved: The Story of the Duke and Duchess of Windsor, 1974
  - Masters, J.G., Stories of the Far West, 1935, autographed
  - Mattes, M.J., The Great Platte River Road, 1969
  - Matthews, B., An Introduction to American Literature, 1911
  - McCuen, J.R., A.C. Winkler, Readings for Writers, 1974
  - McGlashen, C.F., History of the Donner Party, 1947
  - McManigal, J.W., G. Heilman, Farm Town: A Memoir of the 1930's, 1974, (severe water-damage)
- Books, 1891-1974 (Box 16)
  - Meacham, W.E., Old Oregon Trail, 1948
  - Mercer, A.S., The Banditti of the Plains, 1954
  - Michener, J.A., Centennial, 1974 (severe water-damage)
  - Miller, F.T. (ed.), The Photographic History of the Civil War, 1911
    Vol. 5: Forts and Artillery
    Vol. 7: Prisons and Hospitals
    Vol. 8: Soldier Life, Secret Service
    Vol. 9: Poetry and Eloquence
    Vol. 10: Armies and Leaders
  - Minnesota in the Civil War and Indian War 1861-1865, Vols. 1-2, 1891
- Books, 1867-1974 (Box 17)
  - Mokler, A.J., Transition of the West, 1927
  - Montgomery, T.T., L. Mosier, I. Bethel, The Growth of Oklahoma, 1935
  - Morgan, J., Abraham Lincoln: The Boy and the Man, 1908
  - Muench, J., Salt Lake City: A Pictorial Study, 1947
  - Newman, E., Strictly Speaking, 1974
  - Nixon, O.W., How Marcus Whitman Saved Oregon, 1895
  - Peattie, D.C., Forward the Nation, 1942
  - Potter, D.M. (ed.), Trail to California: The Overland Journal of Vincent Geiger and Wakeman Bryarly, 1945
  - Rice, H.S., Someone Cares, 1972
  - Richardson, A.D., Beyond the Mississippi, 1867
  - Roosevelt, E., Book of Common Sense Etiquette, 1962
  - Rosen, B., The Science of Handwriting Analysis, 1965
  - Sheehan, D.H., This is America, My Country, Vols. 1-2, 1952
  - Sheldon, A.E., Nebraska: Old and New, 1937
  - Snyder,, R.C., H.H. Wilson, Roots of Political Behavior, 1949
- Books, 1909-1972 (Box 18)
  - Spaulding, K.A. (ed), On the Oregon Trail: Robert Stuart's Journey of Discovery 1812-1813, 1953
  - Standley, M.G., The Story of the Christ, no date
  - Stewart, G.R., Ordeal by Hunger: The Story of the Donner Party, 1936
  - Stratton, R.B., Captivity of the Oatman Girls, 1909
  - Strunk, W., E.B. White, The Elements of Style, 1972
  - Trenholm, V.C., M. Carley, Wyoming Pageant, 1946, autographed
  - Tressler, J.C., M.B. Shelmadine, Elementary English in Action, Grade 8, 1935
  - Van Der Meer, F., C. Mohrmann, Atlas of the Early Christian World, 1959
  - Warren, E.S., Memoirs of the West: The Spaldings, no date
  - Warriner, J.E., Handbook of English, 1951
  - Watch Tower Bible and Tract Society, This Means Everlasting Life, 1950
  - Webster, K., The Gold Seekers of '49, 1917
  - Wescott, G., The Grandmothers, 1927
  - West, W.M., The Story of Man's Early Progress, 1920
  - Whitman Publishing Company, My Book of Golden Thoughts, 1931
  - Wilson, E.N., H.R. Driggs, The White Indian Boy: The Story of Uncle Nick Among the Shoshones, 1919
  - Wise, W.H. (ed), The American Scrap Book, 1928
  - Wright, H.B., Their Yesterdays, 1912
  - Wyoming Writers' Project, Wyoming: A Guide to its History, Highways, and People, 1952
- Books, 1897-1977 (Box 19)
  - Local and limited publications
    - Personal and family histories
      - Ashby, George F., Major General Grenville M. Dodge, 1947
      - Budlong, Caroline Gale, Memories of Pioneer Days in Oregon and Washington Territories, 1949
      - Cannon, Miles, Toward the Setting Sun, 1953
      - Chambers, Edith Kerns, Genealogical Narrative: A History of Three Pioneer Families, the Kerns, Popes and Gibsons, 1943
      - Frank Leslie Chambers 1865-1946, no author, no date
      - Cole, George E., Early Oregon: Jottings of Personal Recollections of a Pioneer of 1850, 1905
      - Cuthbertson, William C. (ed), Memories of Ayrshire, Illinois and Kansas by the Family of Alexander Cuthbertson 1813-60 et al, 1972
      - Lathrop, George and Luke Voorhees, Some Pioneer Recollections (also statements of John Sinclair and George McKinstry regarding Donner Party), 1927
      - Nelson, O.N. (ed), History of the Scandinavians and Successful Scandinavians in the United States, 1904
      - Letters of Edgar Wilson Nye, ed. by N.O. Rush, 1950, with insert on the Southpass Press at the University of Wyoming Library
      - Ostrander, A.B., After 60 Years, 1925
      - Fifty Years of the Virginian, letters of Owen Wister displayed at the fiftieth anniversary exhibition, 1952
      - Wood, Erskine, Days with Chief Joseph, no date, (imperfect copy - 2 pages printed alternating with 2 pages blank)
    - Local histories
      - Montana
        - Masters, Joseph G., Shadows Fall Across the Little Horn - Custer's Last Stand, 1951 with biographical insert on author
        - Rickey, Don, History of Custer Battlefield, 1967
      - Ohio
        - Allen, Rollin, "Daniel Washington", Tales of a Tavern, 1956, regarding Freemasons of Norwich and Muskingum County
        - Schneider, Norris F., Muskingum County Courthouse 1877-1977, 1977
      - Oregon & Washington
        - Douthit, Mary Osborn (ed), The Souvenir of Western Women, 1905
        - Eells, Myron, A Reply to Professor Bourne's "The Whitman Legend", 1902
        - Jones, Nard, Puget Sound Profiles, Vols. 1-2, 1961-1963
        - Richardson, David, Magic Island: A Treasure-Trove of San Juan Island Lore, 1970
        - Steeves, Sarah Hunt, Book of Remembrance of Marion County, Oregon, Pioneers 1840-1860, 1927
      - Wyoming
        - Calico Hill, published by the Jolly Dry Farmers' Club (Laramie County), 1973
        - Cheyenne Landmarks, and Early Cheyenne Homes 1880-1890, published by Laramie County Chapter of Wyoming State Historical Society, 1975 & 1976, 2 items
        - Hall, Charles "Pat" (ed), Documents of Wyoming Heritage, 1976
        - Hillsdale Heritage, published by Hillsdale Homemakers Club, 1976, includes autobiographical article by W.W. Morrison; with inserts - descriptive literature and newspaper clipping
        - Morris, Robert C., Collections of the Wyoming Historical Society, Vol. 1, 1897
        - Munkres, Robert L., Saleratus and Sagebrush: The Oregon Trail Through Wyoming, 1974, with insert - photocopy of newspaper clipping
        - The Vanished Frontier, published by Wyoming Pioneer Association, 1929
- Books, 1910-1976 (Box 20)
  - Local and limited publications
    - Poetry
      - Allen, Rollin A., Ohio: A Historic Poem, 1953, autographed
      - Cook, Marion, Where Flows Hood River, 1917
      - Cooper, Clara Chassell, Recorded Insights, 1976, autographed
      - Pingree, Edna Barron, Along My Way, no date
      - Thomas, D.G., Overland and Underground: Poems of the West and Its Mines, 1912
      - Weeks, Ida Ahlborn, Poems, 1910
- Pamphlets And Other Printed Materials, 1938-1971 (Box 20)
  - Americana
    - General
      - "Americana", rare book catalog, no date
      - "The Louisiana Purchase", by Bernard DeVoto, 1953
      - Old Oregon Trail, 1 page leaflet
      - The flag, the presidents, Declaration of Independence, D.A.R., etc., 1947-1962, 6 items
    - Virginia-Louisiana
      - Historic Williamsburg, 1951
      - St. Louis Cathedral of New Orleans, 1947
    - Ohio-Illinois-Missouri
      - "The Wonderful World of Ohio", 1965
      - Lincoln Heritage Trail Guide, no date
      - "Missouri: Heart Of The Nation" the Scruggs-Vandervoort-Barney art collection, no date
    - Nebraska-Colorado-Wyoming-South Dakota
      - The Harold Warp Pioneer Village at Minden, Nebraska, no date
      - "Cliff Dwellings Of The Mesa Verde", 1959
      - "How To Get The Most Out Of The Grand Tetons", no date
      - Deadwood, South Dakota, 1948
    - Utah-Nevada-Arizona
      - Utah Centennial place mats, featuring prominent early day Mormons, 1947, 21 items
      - Las Vegas-Hoover Dam-Lake Mead National Recreation Area, no date
      - "The Story of Boulder Dam", 1941
    - Washington
      - Whitman National Monument, 1948
      - Washington Centennial Commemorative Booklet, 1945
  - Europe: Holland-Italy-Switzerland-Greece
    - Tourist brochures, maps, menus, airline tickets and schedules, etc., 1960's, 41 items
  - Railroads
    - Histories of the Union Pacific, 1959-1969, 3 items
    - Union Pacific through Wyoming, 1968
    - "Year Of Decision: Clear Track Or Crisis", an address by Daniel P. Loomis, president Association of American Railroads, 1959
    - Historic Locomotives, 4 color etch prints by Robert Kern, no date
  - Religion
    - Booklets of inspirational thoughts, tracts, poems, 1952-1971 or undated, 7 items
    - First United Methodist Church, Cheyenne, Wyoming 1876-1973, listing and picturing Mr. and Mrs. W.W. Morrison as members, 1973
  - Speech Course
    - A New Self-Teaching Course in Practical English and Effective Speech, lessons 2-15, by E.B. Hunter, 1938, 2 notebooks
  - Miscellaneous
    - Camera Club membership applications (blank), 15 items
    - Camera equipment advertising, 1 item
    - Notebook (blank) advertising Colorado Fuel & Iron
- Periodicals, 1891-1954 (Box 21)
  - State and local historical reviews
    - Idaho State Historical Society Biennial Report, 18th, 1941-1942
    - Indiana Magazine Of History, vol.47 no.3, 1951
    - The Palimpsest, vol.33 no.9, published by the State Historical Society of Iowa, 1952
    - The Missouri Historical Review, vol.25 no.4; vol.43 nos. 2-4; vol.44 nos.1-4; vol.45 nos.1-2; 1931, 1949-1951
    - Missouri Historical Society Collections, vol.4 no.1, 1912
    - Nebraska History, vol.30 nos.1-2; vol.33 no.4; vol.34 nos.1-4; vol.35 nos.1-3; 1949, 1952-1954
    - The Oregon Historical Quarterly, vol.29 no.1, 1928
    - Oregon Pioneer Association Transactions of annual reunions, 19th-21st, 33rd, 40th, 46th-50th, 53rd; 1891-1893, 1905, 1912, 1918-1922, 1925, (2 copies of 1893)
    - The Utah Genealogical And Historical Magazine, vol.16 nos.2-3; 1925
    - Utah Historical Quarterly, vol.19 nos.1-4 bound as one volume and titled West from Fort Bridger: the Pioneering of the Immigrant Trails Across Utah 1846-1850, featuring original diaries and journals, ed. by J.R. Korns, 1951
    - The Pacific Northwest Quarterly, vol.30 no.2; vol.33 no.1; vol.35 no.4; vol.37 no.3; vol.38 no.4; published by the University of Washington; 1939, 1942, 1944, 1946, 1947
    - The Washington Historian, vol.2 no.3, 1901
    - The Washington Historical Quarterly, vol.1 no.1; vol.11 no.4; vol.12 nos.1-4; vol.13 no.1; vol.14 no.2; vol.18 nos.3-4; 1906, 1920-1927
- Periodicals, 1908-1972 (Box 22)
  - State and local historical reviews
    - Annals Of Wyoming, vol.11 nos.1-3; vol.12 nos.1-4; vol.13 nos.1-4; vol.14 nos.1-4; vol.18 no.2; vol.21 no.2/3; vol.22 no.2; vol.23 no.2; vol.27 no.2; vol.43 no.2; 1939-1942, 1946, 1949, 1950, 1951, 1955, 1971
    - Bits And Pieces, vol.1 no.2, published in Newcastle, Wyoming, 1965
    - The Wyoming Archaeologist, vol.7 no.3, 1964
    - The Wyoming Pioneer, vol.1 nos.1-6 (2 copies of no.4); vol.2 nos.1-6; vol.3 no.1; 1940-1942
    - Wyoming State Historical Department Proceedings, 2nd biennial report, 1922
  - Miscellaneous
    - American Heritage, vol.4 no.4, featuring Washington State Centennial, 1953
    - The Highwayman, vol.22 no.1, with article "Stories In Stone" about Morrison and Oregon Trail graves, 1972, 2 copies
    - Indian Notes, vol.6 no.2; vol.7 no.1; 1929-1930 and index 1927
    - The Mentor, vol.13 no.7, featuring American Southwest, 1925
    - The Midwest Review, vol.8 no.7/8, 1927
    - The Pacific Monthly, vol.9 no.3, with article "Our Contemporaneous Ancestors" about Oregon pioneers, 1908
    - The Railroad Telegrapher, vol.80 no.6, 1963
- Scrapbooks, 1961-1972 (Box 22)
  - Clippings from Reader's Digest regarding nature, society, health, religion, world affairs and history, 3 notebooks
- Scrapbooks, 1945-1977 (Box 23)
  - Clippings from Reader's Digest, Grit, Sunshine Magazine, various Wyoming and Ohio newspapers, regarding nature, society, health, religion, world affairs and history, 6 notebooks
- Audio Recordings, 1963-1970 (Box 24 (clamshell))
  - Elva Ingram, talk given by W.W. Morrison at grave site, cassette tape, 1970
  - "New Light On Old Glory", written and narrated by Howard R. Driggs, 78 rpm record and 16mm reel-to-reel tape, 1963
  - Trinity Lutheran Church, Gillette, Wyoming, 16mm reel-to-reel tape, no date
  - Unidentified, 16mm reel-to-reel tape
- Book, no date (Box 24 (clamshell))
  - Frank Leslie's Illustrated History of the Civil War (title on cover and spine is Famous Leaders and Battle Scenes of the Civil War); binding damaged; pages loose, missing and out of order
- Certificates, 1914-1975 (Box 24 (clamshell))
  - Of graduation and appreciation, 4 items
- Maps And Plats, 1924-1967 (Box 25 (clamshell))
  - Atlases, published by Rand-McNally, 1924, 1964, 1967, 3 items
- Maps And Plats, 1848-1972 (Box 26 (clamshell))
  - Forts and Stations
    - Fort Fetterman, plan hand-drawn, 1937
    - Fort Kearney, photocopies of plans, 1849, 1852, 1860's, 3 items
    - Fort Laramie, photocopies of plan, no date, and drawing, 1867, 2 items
    - Fort Phil Kearny, photocopies of post returns for Fort Phil Kearny (Dec. 1866) and Fort Laramie (Jan. 1867) after Fetterman Massacre, 2 items
    - Stations: Platte Bridge, Deer Creek, LaBonte, Horse Shoe; redrawn from Caspar Collins' 1863-1864 drawings in 1935, 1 item
  - Trails and Territories: full routes and areas
    - Carte du Missouri (map of the Missouri and Platte Rivers), copy of 1802 publication, very fragile